Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler Texas Jewish collection, Inclusive: 1827-2009, undated, Bulk: 1972-2004
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler Texas Jewish collection
Inclusive: 1827-2009, undated, Bulk: 1972-2004
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
855
Gandler Family Papers
Gandler, Ima Joy Chodorow, 1929 - 2010
45 document boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder
The Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler Texas Jewish collection houses Ima Joy Gandler’s family and personal papers as well as genealogical information of Waco Jewish families. Gandler’s participation and interests in numerous organizations is also documented. Items include clippings, correspondence, newsletters, bulletins, photographs, legal documents, organizational records, and other print materials and audiovisual media.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler was born 1929 October 25 in Waco, Texas, to Nathan and Miriam Borschow Chodorow. She was a 1946 Waco High School graduate and attended the University of Texas. Ima Joy Chodorow married Jacob E. "Jake" Gandler on 1950 June 25 and they had three children; Sharlane Michaele, Laura, and Howard.
As an active member of Waco Temple Rodef Sholom, Ima Joy Gandler began collecting materials on Texas Jewish Culture in the 1970s as the Temple neared its 100th Anniversary. She began with a local archive to document each confirmation class and moved on to document the history of the Waco Jewish Community as well as Jewish Communities across Texas.
In 1980 Ima Joy became a founding member of the Texas Jewish Historical Society and promoted the interest of Texas Jewish History locally, throughout Texas, and the United States. She was also an active member in organizations such as the National Council of Jewish Women, National Federation of Temple Sisterhoods, Jewish Federation of Waco and Central Texas, and the Greater Waco Interfaith Conference. Her participation often included the role of archivist, board member, or other governing title.
In addition to her religious interests, Gandler used her research skills to further her genealogical searches and help others do the same. In doing so she was able to collect several family histories from the Waco Jewish Community. Ima Joy was also a patron of the arts and enjoyed travel. She regularly supported the Waco Hippodrome Theatre as a season ticket holder and visited larger cities such as Dallas and New York to attend shows as well.
Ima Joy Gandler died on 2010 January 25. She is buried at Rodef Sholom Cemetery in Waco, Texas.
Scope and Content
Ima Joy Gandler’s personal interests and community involvement contributed to a broad collection of Waco and Texas Jewish history which she distributed as photocopies and original materials to repositories such as the American Jewish Archives in Cincinnati, Ohio; the Dolph Briscoe Center for American History at the University of Texas in Austin, and The Texas Collection at Baylor University in Waco, Texas. The Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler Texas Jewish Collection houses Gandler’s personal and family papers in addition to highlighting her genealogical interests and participation with numerous organizations.
The Family series consists of materials produced by and about Gandler’s family. The Borschows, Chodorows, and Gandlers provide a bulk of the information, but other branches are represented as well. The Personal series is an extension of family papers but focus specifically on Ima Joy’s activities. Her interests in the arts, travel, research, and personal relationships are documented in addition to her philanthropic and organizational participation. An original manuscript and printed copy of the book Pioneer Jews of Waco by Rabbi Mordecai Podet are also included.
The Genealogy series consists of original and photocopied materials documenting activities, events, and accomplishments of individuals and families within the Waco Jewish Community. Documentation shows that original materials were made available to Ima Joy Gandler and returned to the families after photocopying with knowledge that the information would be distributed through the Texas Collection at Baylor University and [Waco] Temple Rodef Sholom. Multiple generations of families with deep ties to the Waco Jewish Community are documented as well as several others who once lived in the area but have moved away. Notable names include Englander, Goldstein, Sanger, Levy, Naman, Lipsitz, and Harelik. Also included are notecards created by Gandler which outline family lineages.
The Organizations series documents Gandler’s involvement and interests in the broader Jewish Community. As a member of local, regional, and national organizations she collected materials of such groups as the Greater Waco Interfaith Conference, National Council for Jewish Women, and the Texas Jewish Historical Society (TJHS). She also collected material on Jewish congregations throughout Texas, identifying lost or dwindling Jewish communities in addition to those still thriving. Organizations she supported financially can also be found. Some include the Greene Family Camp, Texas A&M Hillel, and the United States Holocaust Memorial. Information on each organization varies based upon Ima Joy’s involvement from casual interest to active member or officer. This is most evident in congregational files as some have only one or two items while others are more robust with multiple files.
In the General series, groups of records that did not accurately fit into another series are collected. Material related to the Archie Hoppenstein papers and items from Lena Lynn and the Jolly Huaco Garden Club are present. Land title abstracts and deeds are also included as there is no clear connection to whom they belonged.
Arrangement
The collection had no previous order. Items are now arranged into five series: I. Family, II. Personal, III. Genealogy, IV. Organizations, and V. General.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 855. Acquired 1974-09-00
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Nate Chodorow papers, Inclusive: 1931-1986, undated, Bulk: 1939-1986
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. “Ima Joy Chodorow Gandler.” Memorial #47227387. Databases. Accessed 2019 November 14.
“Obituaries: Ima Joy Gandler,” Jewish Herald-Voice (Houston, TX), 2010 February 4. Accessed 2019 November 12.
Vogel, Vicky. “Ima Joy’s Waco.” Texas Jewish historical Society March (2015): 14-19. Accessed 2019 November 12.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Gandler, Ima Joy Chodorow, 1929-2010.
Subjects (Organizations)
Congregation Agudath Jacob (Waco, Tex.).; Jewish Federation of Waco and Central Texas.; National Council of Jewish Women.; National Federation of Temple Sisterhoods.; Southern Jewish Historical Society (U.S.); Temple Emanu-El (Dallas, Tex.); Temple Rodef Sholom (Waco, Tex.).; Texas Jewish Historical Society.; Union of American Jewish Congregations.
Subjects
Annual reports.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Invitations.; Jewish women -- Texas -- Waco -- Societies and clubs.; Jews -- Genealogy.; Jews -- Texas -- Waco -- History.; Legal instruments.; Newsletters.; Obituaries.; Records (Documents); Synagogues -- Texas.; Waco High School (Waco, Tex.)
Genres
Photographs.; VHS.
- Family, 1900-2006, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Family series is dated 1900-2006 and contains records and general information regarding Ima Joy’s Borschow, Chodorow, and Gandler relatives. Materials include legal documents, photographs, newspaper clippings, correspondence, certificates and ledgers. The series is arranged alphabetically and is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - Borschow Family, 1900-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borschow, Pearl (Grossman, Werbner, Schaffer), 1920-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Borschow, Rebecca, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Borschow, Sarah (Rita Barr), 1934-2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Borschow-Chodorow Family Photographs, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brown Family, 1983-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chodorow Family, 1941-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chodorow, Bessie, 1929-2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chodorow, Gretta, 1934-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chodorow, Hilton Ivan, 1936-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chodorow, Max, 1923-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chodorow, Miriam, 1963-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chodorow, Miriam: Correspondence, 1959-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chodorow, Miriam: Correspondence, 1980-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate), 1912-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate): Business Advertisements, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate): Business Inventories, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate): Business Papers, 1938-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate): Land Sale and Tax Documents, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chodorow, Nathan (Nate) and Miriam, 1962-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chodorow, Stanley, 1975-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chodorow, Stanley Ray, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chodorow, Steven Craig, 1971-1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chodorow-Gandler Family Photographs, 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Foerderer, Nancy, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gandler Family, 1980-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gandler, Fannie (Beerman), 1916-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gandler, Howard Irwin, 1922-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Gandler, Ima Joy (Chodorow), 1942-2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gandler, Ima Joy (Chodorow): High School Graduation Party Guest Book, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gandler, Jacob Emanuel (1 of 2), 1936-2003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gandler, Jacob Emanuel (2 of 2), 1936-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gandler, Jacob Emanuel: Condolences, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gandler, Jacob Emanuel: Masons and Scottish Rite, 1952-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gandler, Jacob Emanuel: Shabbos Service and Dedication, Memorial, 1992 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Gandler, Jacob and Ima Joy, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gandler, Jacob and Ima Joy: Financial Papers, 1955-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gandler, Jacob and Ima Joy: Rental Property Ledgers, 1961-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gandler, Laura Beth, 1953-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gandler, Sharlane Michaele, 1951-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gandler-Snider Engineering Company, 1953-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kator, Irv and Ida (Gandler), 1938-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Maslovati, Moishe, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pulman, Minnie (Gandler), 1944-2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Werbner, Anne (Chodorow), 1907-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Zlots, Rachel and Isaac, 1930-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Personal, 1876-2009, undated; 2
  The Personal series, dated 1876-2009, documents the works, interests, and life of Ima Joy Gandler. Clippings, photographs, annual reports, newsletters, invitations, correspondence, greeting cards, research notes, pamphlets, and other printed material are included. The series is arranged alphabetically by topic and is in good condition.
  Cassette tape; Photographic print; Video home system (VHS) tapes
  - American Jewish Historical Society: Annual Conference, Hot Springs, Arkansas, 1984-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Art Center of Waco, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Arts: [Fort Worth] Casa Manana Theatre, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arts: General, 1983-2002 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arts: Play, Sons of David, Daughters of Miriam, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Arts: Programs, 1896-1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Arts: Ticket Stubs, 1966-2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Arts: Waco Hippodrome Theatre, 1995-1999 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Balak Parchment, Baylor University, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - C.A.J. Reunion [Congregation Agudath Jacob], undated (Box 2 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Caritas, 1989-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Downtown Waco, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Clippings: General, 1887-1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: Jewish Interests, 1891-2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Politics, 1981-2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Service Project, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: [Waco] CenTex Zoo, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Clippings: [Waco] Temple Rodef Sholom, 1928-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: [Waco] Temple Rodef Sholom, Sisterhood, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cooper Foundation Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Amiel Wohl, circa 1979-2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Announcements, 1978-2008 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Condolences, 1991-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Country Clubs, 1985-2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: General, 1976-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Holiday Cards and Letters, 1974-2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Invitations, Bar/Bat Mitzvahs, 1989-2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Invitations, General, 1973-2004 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Invitations, Organizations, 1976-2007 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Rabbi Charles Blumenthal, 1911-1938 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Research, 1973-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Solicitations and Thank-you’s, 1975-2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Texas Jewish Historical Society, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Thank You Cards, 1957-2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Thank You Cards, 1987-2009 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Thank You Letters, 1983-1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Weddings and Anniversaries, 1971-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Weddings and Anniversaries, 1971-2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - De Cordova Dedication and Luncheon (1 of 2), 1986 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 2)
  - De Cordova Dedication and Luncheon (2 of 2), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - De Cordova Historical Marker Dedication, 1986 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Delicious Memories Cookbook, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Delta Phi Epsilon, 1983-1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Downtown Waco Public Improvement District, 1995-2005 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - First National Bank of Central Texas: First Choice Club, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Friends of Golden Acres, Dallas Home for Jewish Aged, 1963-2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Genealogy Resources, 1980-2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Friends of Waco High Schools, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Histories, Waco and Central Texas, 1876-1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Israel, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Kallah of Texas Rabbis, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lindenwood College, 1986-1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Membership Cards, 1975-2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Museums, 1965-2002 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Museums, Holocaust, 1994-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - National WWII Monument, 2002-2004 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Parent Teacher Association (PTA), 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pathfinders Award, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Downtown Waco, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: General, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: General, circa 1900-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: General, 1979-2004 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Greene Family camp, Holocaust Sculpture, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Goldie Levy Birthday, 1993, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Jewish Federation of Waco and Central Texas, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Organizations, 1919-1947 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Pennsylvania, Washington D.C., New York, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Texas Air Expo at Texas State Technical Institute, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: Texas Jewish Historical Society, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: Texas Jewish Historical Society, 1996-2002 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Photographs: [Waco] Jewish Families, 1905-1947 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: Unidentified Family Photographs, circa 1876 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Pioneer Jews of Waco, Book by Mordecai Podet, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Pioneer Jews of Waco, Original Manuscript by Mordecai Podet, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Politics, 1981-2006 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Presentations, 1983-2005 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Programs, 1929-2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jewish History in Texas, circa 1971-1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Research: Reports and Journals, 1972-2006 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Research: Resources, Virginia, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Research Notes: General, circa 1930-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Research Notes: Labatt Family, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Richfield High School Class of 1971: Reunion, 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Richfield High School Class of 1974: Reunion, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ritual Guides, 1949-1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Talitha Koum, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Travel, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Travel, 1960-2006 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - [Waco] Brazos Club, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Waco, General, 1965-1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Waco Education Foundation: Annual Report, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Waco Foundation: Annual Report, 2001-2006 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Waco High School: Faculty and Student Directory, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Waco High School Class of 1934: Reunion, 1994-2004 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Waco High School Class of 1939: Reunion, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Waco High School Class of 1945: Reunion, 1986-2005 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Directories, 1976-2006 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Photographs, 1981-2008 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Planning, 1975-2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Video (1 of 2), 1981 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 3)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Video (2 of 2), 1981 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 4)
  - Waco High School Class of 1946: Reunion Video, 1986 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 5)
  - [Waco] Hillcrest Hospital: Annual Report, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Waco Jewish Federation Texas Sesquicentennial: Community Day Event, 1986 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 6)
  - Waco Jewish History, circa 1909-1981 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Waco Tercentenary Dinner, 1955 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 3)
  - [Wimberly] Camp Young Judea, 1972-1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Genealogy, 1827-2009, undated; 3
  The Genealogy series, dated 1827 -2009, includes items such as legal documents, immigration papers, birth announcements, obituaries, and newspaper clippings. Also included are certificates and invitations for various events including confirmations, bar/bat mitzvahs, weddings, and birthdays. Photographs and reproduction photographs have been included as well. The series is arranged alphabetically by family surname. The series is in good condition.
  Cassette tape; Photographic print
  - Genealogy Cards: Adams-Friedman, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Genealogy Cards: Gabber-Kuttner, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Genealogy Cards: Lachman-Pollock, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Genealogy Cards: Raphael-Zigel, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Abel-Avnet, 1947-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Archenhold, 1900-1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Arin, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Barshop-Brand, 1908-2009 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bahme, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Bauer-Lipinsky, 1920-2006 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Beerman, Adolph: Ledgers, 1968-1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Bell, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Blumenthal, 1900-1986 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bowman, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Brenner, 1977-1983 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Brickman, 1929-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Chaznow-Corman, 1933-1996 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Cohen, 1895-2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Corwin, 1979-2007 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dimpson-Domnau, 1975-1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Dessenberg, 1896-1933 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Diamond, 1945-1954 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Donchin, 1920-1980 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Ellis, 1975-1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Elsbach, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Englander, 1945-1998 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Epstein, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Everet, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Farbstein-Frimel, 1912-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Fred, circa 1900-1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Freed, 1973-1985 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Freeman, 1977-1985 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Friedlander, 1903-1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Friedman, 1891-1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Frindell, 1914-1986 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Garfinkle-Greenstein, 1960-2008 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Gardner, 1983-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Genecov, 1942-1985 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Ginsburg, 1910-1995 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Goldberg, 1981-1994 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Goldstein, 1884-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Goodman, 1895-1998 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Green, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Halpern-Householder, 1891-1998 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Haber, 1869-1992 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Harelik, circa 1912-2004 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Harelik interview, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Item 4)
  - Hirsch, 1827-2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hirschberg-Beer, 1843-1944 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hoffman, 1918-2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hoppenstein, 1955-2006 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hoppenstein, Jacob, Oral History (1 of 2), undated (Box 2 OVZ, Item 5)
  - Hoppenstein, Jacob, Oral History (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Israel, 1928-1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Jack-Johnson, 1975-2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Karff-Krim, 1959-2007 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Kahn, 1872-1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Kantrovich, 1903-1999 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Koppman, 1908-1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Kost, 1956-1996 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Kuttner-Gabert, 1861-1940 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Lesser-Lynn, 1959-1998 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Labens, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Lacy, 1973-1999 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Lacy, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Landman, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Lawrence, 1960-1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Lazerowitz, 1910-1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Lazarus-Novich, 1898-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Levi, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Levy, 1905-2006 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Lipinsky, 1983-2004 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Lipsitz, 1961-1991 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Loewenstein, 1899-1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mandel-Myers, 1842-2004 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Macht, 1924-1953 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Marcuis, 1928-1995 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Marks, 1975-1986 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Migel, 1885-1951 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Miller, 1956-1988 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miller: Photographs, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Naman-Nussbaum, 1979-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Newirth, 1895-1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Novich, 1985-1996 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Oehringen-Passel, 1927-2006 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Pearlstone, 1893-1974 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Podet, 1955-1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pulman, 1983-2001 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Raden-Rosenthal, 1974-2001 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Rapoport, 1913-2003 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Roffman, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Rogers, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Rosenfeld, 1943-2002 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Schwartz-Stupak, circa 1968-1998 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sachs, 1925-1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Sanger, 1887-1994 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Sanger, 1951 (Drawer C 13. Folder. 1)
  - Schaevitz, 1982-1988 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Scharff, 1982-1991 (Box 15, Folder 17)